rapid7.com 2018-12-05

# Privacy Policy | Rapid7

Rapid7 Privacy Policy 

Last Updated: May 25, 2018

_Our quest to accelerate insight for security and technology practitioners requires collecting and processing a significant amount of data. Ensuring your data is used only in a manner consistent with your expectations is a responsibility we take very seriously, and we back the privacy statements below with layers of security to safeguard your data._

Rapid7, we, and us refers to Rapid7, Inc., Rapid7 LLC and any of our corporate affiliates.

This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use and disclose information you provide to us, including personal information, by which we mean information that would allow us to determine your identity when you engage with us. For example, we may receive your information when you use our solutions or services or otherwise interact with us (for example, by using our websites or attending our events). In addition, this Privacy Policy covers the information we may collect through our research initiatives.

This Privacy Policy also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy carefully when using or providing information to us through our sites, solutions, and services. You understand that by using our sites, solutions, and services, you are accepting our practices as described in this Privacy Policy.

## What kinds of information do we collect?

### Information you provide directly to us

For example, we collect information you provide in order to access our solutions, use our sites, subscribe to our content, or register for an activity associated with Rapid7. This may include, but is not limited to, your name, email address, telephone number, and mailing address.

If you make a purchase from Rapid7, become one of our vendors, or otherwise establish a relationship with us that involves financial transactions, we collect information about those transactions. This may include, but is not limited to, your credit or debit card information, account and authentication information, tax identifiers, and other billing, delivery, and contact details.

### Information we collect to deliver and improve our solutions and services

In order to provide our solutions and services to you, we must necessarily collect certain information automatically. This also helps us to ensure that our solutions and services are operating correctly. The types of information we collect include: 

  * Device and network data
  * User and system behavior
  * Application logs
  * Organizational information
  * Other relevant machine data  

We also collect information about the solutions you use and how you use them, such as how often you access our products and which features you use most frequently. This is done in an effort to improve your experience with our solutions. For example, we may use this information to reach out to you if you seem “stuck” on a certain process within the solution, to make our solutions more intuitive, or to enhance the solution’s most popular features. 

On our sites, Rapid7 and our third-party partners collect information using cookies and other tracking technologies. Please see our full Cookie Notice, which includes information on how to control or opt out of these cookies and tracking technologies.  

### Information from third-parties

We receive various types of information from third-parties on some occasions, such as when we jointly offer services or sponsor events. We also collect data from third party security providers and online databases in connection with our research activities that relate to active or historic threats, vulnerabilities, and risks around the world. This can include data like domain names, IP addresses, email accounts, and usernames that are associated with security risks (for example, known compromised accounts and usernames), and we use this information to enhance the security services we provide to you.

Return to top

## How do we use this information?

### To deliver, improve, and develop our offerings

We are able to deliver our solutions and services, understand the behavior of attackers, and better help our customers keep their environments safe by using the information we collect above.

In general, we only process our customers' information to deliver our offerings on their behalf. Although we may collect the information listed above, we do not access information that we process on our customer’s behalf, such as user, network, vulnerability, incident, or asset information, unless our customers have requested we do so to investigate issues with our solution or carry out a service.

### To communicate with you 

We use your information to communicate with you about our solutions, services, features, surveys, newsletters, offers, promotions, and events, and to provide other news or information about Rapid7 and our partners, in accordance with your communications preferences.

We will also use your information to respond to you when you contact us.

### To conduct research initiatives

The vast majority of the data we collect through our research initiatives is data that’s publicly available. It is collected to educate and enrich the security community, and foster secure adoption of technology. For example, one of our research initiatives uses the metadata from publicly expose services to identify large-scale misconfigurations and vulnerabilities in consumer, enterprise, and critical infrastructure systems.

Return to top

## How is this information shared?

### With organizations participating in or promoting research

Information related to the research we conduct may be shared with various research and security organizations, including academic institutions or publications, but only when this information is already freely publicly available and/or non-identifiable. We may also publish this research online on our website or through third party social media sites.

### With third-party vendors, consultants, service providers, or other business partners

Some third parties provide services on our behalf and may require access to your information to carry out that work, including billing, customer support, etc. These service providers are authorized to use your information only as necessary to provide the services in scope and are subject to strict contractual controls to protect the confidentiality and security of your information. If you’re a customer of our products or services, our list of subprocessors is available here.

### In the case of a merger, sale, financing, or acquisition

We may share or transfer your information in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company. You will subsequently be notified via email and/or via a prominent notice on our sites of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.  The recipient of your information will be informed of the need to protect your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Return to top

## How do we respond to legal requests?

We may share personal information with companies, organizations, or individuals outside of Rapid7 if we have a good-faith belief that access, use, preservation, or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to:

    * Protect against harm to the rights, property, or safety of Rapid7, our customers or the public.
    * Meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request.
    * Detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues.

Return to top

## How do we operate our global services?

Rapid7 may share information internally across our parent, subsidiary, and affiliate companies or with third parties for the purposes defined in this policy. Information collected within the European Economic Area (“EEA”) may, for example, be transferred to countries outside of the EEA (including the United States of America) for the purposes as described in this policy.

 We have certified our compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield, and our commitments under the EU-US Privacy Shield apply whenever we transfer personal information from the EEA to our parent, subsidiary, and affiliate companies in the United States of America. For more information please see here.

Return to top

## How will we notify you of changes to this policy?

We may update the Rapid7 Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any change in how we use your personal information we will take steps to notify you, which may include notifying you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this site prior to the change becoming effective. If required by applicable data protection laws, we will seek your consent to any material change in how we use your personal information before that change takes effect.

We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Return to top

## How can you manage or delete information about your organization?

### Correcting and updating your information

Upon request, Rapid7 will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct, update or request deletion of your personal information by emailing us at [privacy@rapid7.com](mailto:privacy@rapid7.com). We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe and in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

### Communications opt-out

We may use your information to send you a newsletter or other marketing communications in accordance with your communication preferences. You may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing communications at any time by following the unsubscribe instructions included in the newsletters or communications. Alternatively, you can opt-out of receiving such newsletters and communications by contacting us at [privacy@rapid7.com](mailto:privacy@rapid7.com).

### Customer data

If you opt to end your engagement with Rapid7, you have the opportunity to collect and transfer any data that is possible to export. If you request that Rapid7 delete all of your data, the request will be processed within 14 days.

Return to top

## How secure is my data?

We're a security company, so naturally we take data security very seriously. We use appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect your data against any accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, unauthorised disclosure of, or access to, the information we process.

Return to top

## How long do you keep data for?

If you are a customer, we will retain your information for as long as your account is active, or as needed to provide you products and/or services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide our offerings, contact us at [privacy@rapid7.com](mailto:privacy@rapid7.com). 

In all other cases, we will retain and use your information as necessary for legitimate business reasons, including as needed to comply with our legal obligations, to resolve disputes, and to enforce our agreements.  When we have no ongoing legitimate business reason to process your information, we will either delete or anonymise it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

Return to top

## I'm from the Europe – is there anything else I should know?

### Legal basis for processing personal information

If you are an individual in the European Economic Area, our legal basis for collecting and using your information will depend on the information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.  

However, we will normally collect information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. Where we collect and use your information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), it will normally be obvious from the context what those legitimate interests are.

If we are processing information about you on behalf of a customer in the course of providing our services to them (i.e. as a data processor), then it is our customer's responsibility to determine the legal basis for the processing we conduct on their behalf. If you ask us about information we are processing on behalf of a customer, we will direct you to speak with the relevant customer.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your information, please contact us using the contact details provided below.

### Additional data protection rights

In addition to your rights to access, correct, update and delete your information described above, and your right to opt-out of communications also explained above, you also have the right to object to processing of your information, ask us to restrict processing of your information or to request portability of your information. You can exercise these rights by contacting us using the contact details provided below.

If we have collected and process your information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

If you are unhappy with the way we have processed your information, you have the right to complain to a data protection authority. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. (Contact details for data protection authorities in the European Economic Area are available [here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).) 

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

### EU Data Protection Officer

To contact our EU data protection officer, please e-mail [privacy@rapid7.com](mailto:privacy@rapid7.com).

### EU representative

Our representative in the European Union is Rapid7 International Limited with a registered office at Riverbank House, 2 Swan Lane, London, England, EC4R 3TT.

Return to top

## How can you contact Rapid7 with questions or concerns?

### Mailing Address:

Rapid7, 100 Summer Street, 13th Floor, Boston, MA 02110-2115

### Phone:

1.617.247.1717

### Email:

privacy@rapid7.com

Return to top
